(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-21T01:13:55.581593",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
にゃっはろー！
Nyahallo!
さくらみこ生誕祭2023 始まるよー！
Sakura Miko's Birthday Party 2023 is starting!
箱にあたる陽を横目で眺めて
Glancing sideways at the sunlight hitting the box,
そっと陰る木の根に一人で比べてた
I compared myself alone by the quietly darkening tree roots.
積もる溜息を吹き払うように
As if blowing away the piling sighs,
そんな私を君が見つけてくれたんだ
You were the one who found someone like me.
そう それは恋のような
Yes, it's like a warmth akin to love...
君に笑顔咲かせたら
If we make your smile blossom,
桜風に踊る空
In the sky where cherry blossom winds dance,
君と出会ったこの場所で
at this place where I met you,
どれくらいの思い出ぎゅっとあふれそうになるかな
how many memories will overflow?
君と流した涙は明日の笑顔の糧にしよう
The tears we shed together will become the nourishment for tomorrow's smiles.
膝をついてたってほら何度だっていいよ
Even if you fall to your knees, hey, as many times as it takes is fine.
意地を張って 恥をかいて いじけたって それでも
Putting on a brave face, feeling embarrassed, and being stubborn, even so,
君が傍で見守ってくれたこと わかってるから
I know that you stayed by my side and watched over me.
追い風を受けて とまらない日々も
Receiving a tailwind, even days that feel unstoppable
そっと砕けそうになって 心が渦巻いた
felt like they were breaking, and my heart was churning.
積もる溜息でまた泣きかけても
Even when on the verge of crying again with piling sighs,
あたたかな手でずっと支えてくれたんだ
you supported me all along with your warm hands.
ほら 耳をすませば 一人じゃないから
See, if you listen closely, you're not alone.
諦めかけて 心が閉じても
Even if you give up and your heart closes,
君が背中を押してくれたよね
you pushed me on the back, didn't you?
春の蕾が花開く頃は
When spring buds open into flowers,
隣で笑い合おうね
let's laugh together side by side.
桜風に踊る空
In the sky where cherry blossom winds dance,
君と出会ったこの場所で
at this place where I met you,
どれくらいの思い出ぎゅっとあふれそうになるかな
how many memories will overflow?
君と描くこの花は 未来もきっと残るから
The flowers we draw together will surely remain in the future too.
汗をかいた分は そうさ 強くなれるんだ
The sweat we shed will make us stronger, that's right.
意地を張って 恥をかいて いじけたって それでも
Putting on a brave face, feeling embarrassed, and being stubborn, even so,
君が傍で見守ってくれたから ありがとうだよ
I know that you stayed by my side and watched over me. Thank you so much.
君と出会えたこの空
In the sky where I met you,
これからもっと咲かせるよ
I'll make it bloom even more from now on.
準備できた？ もちろん！
Ready? Of course!
みんなにニコニコして欲しいな 盛り上がっていくぞ！
Let's make everyone smile wide, get excited!
Glory Steady Go!
見つけちゃった大事にしたい想い ぎゅっとぎゅっと抱きしめなきゃこぼれちゃいそう
I want to hold the important feelings I found tightly, so they don't spill out.
胸は秘めずに張っていかなきゃね
I've got to keep holding my chest high without hiding it, right?
ほらほらもっともっと奏でたいエモーション
Come on, let's play out more and more of this emotion!
hurry! hurry! 何時？何時？今すぐ！
Hurry, hurry! When? When? Right now!
what do you want to do? and what do you like? showtime! showtime!
what do you want to be? うーわんだほーい！！！
What do you want to be? Wow-da-ho-i!
伝えたいのは言葉だけじゃないなら メロディ溢れるリズムでいいじゃん
What I want to convey shouldn't just be words, a overflowing melody is fine too.
耳をすませばほら夢ときめいたなら let's dance!! yeah!!
If you tune your ears to dreams and inspirations, let's dance, yeah!
glory! 生きてるって最高！ 歌いたい！
Glory! Being alive is the best! I want to sing!
もっと？(もっと！)もっと夢見ちゃえ！ カラフルなセカイみたいな
More? More! Let's dream more! A colorful world.
steady! steady! 1歩ずつね 踏みしめていこう
Steady! Steady! Let's step forward one step at a time.
wake up! (wake up!) stand up! (stand up!) なりたい自分を目指してgo！
Wake up! Stand up! Aiming to be the self I want to be, go!
この想いのせて歌よ響け！ glory steady go!
Put these feelings into song and let them resonate! Glory steady go!
i wanna be! it's time to smile! it's time to uhh… wao!!! it's time to showtime!
I wanna be! It's time to smile! It's time to... wao! It's time to showtime!
逃げちゃダメ
Don't run away,
避けてちゃダメ
don't avoid it.
後悔なんてしたくないな
I don't want any regrets!
レッツゴー ハッピー
Let's go, happy!
らしく進もう
Let's move forward as we are!
グッデイ 目覚ましより
Good day, more than my alarm...
(早起きの サニーデイ)
(An early-rising sunny day)
今天是 いつもよりも
Today is more than usual,
(ちょっと おしゃれ 頑張った)
(I dressed up a little extra!)
なのに全然 君は全然 気づかないで
And yet, you completely don't notice!
よそ見して るんだ
You're looking away somewhere else.
知らない 乙女心
A maiden's heart you don't know...
教えてあげる
I'll teach it to you!
君が好き ! 素直になって 言えたらどんなに
I like you! If I could just become honest and say it...
So Happy!
How so happy I'd be!
溢れ出す この愛は 甘いだけではありません!
This overflowing love isn't just sweet!
明日が今日より輝いて
May tomorrow shine brighter than today,
幸せになれますように
and make me happy!
ちょっとくらい つよがりなところも許してください
Please forgive my somewhat stubborn sides.
逃げちゃダメ 避けてちゃダメ
Don't run away, don't avoid it,
後悔なんてしたくない
I don't want any regrets!
レッツゴー ハッピー らしく進もう
Let's go, happy, let's move forward as we are!
Happy Strawberry
グッデイ 目覚ましより
Good day, more than my alarm...
(早起きの サニーデイ)
(An early-rising sunny day)
今日は いつもよりも
Today, more than usual...
(ちょっと おしゃれ 頑張った)
(I tried a little extra to dress nicely)
なのに全然 君は全然
And yet, you completely, you completely
気づかないで よそ見してるんだ
Don't notice, you're looking away somewhere else.
知らない 乙女心
A maiden's heart you don't know,
教えてあげる
I'll teach it to you!
君が好き ! 素直になって
I like you! If I could just become honest
言えたらどんなに So Happy!
And say it, how so happy I'd be!
溢れ出す
This overflowing love...
この愛は 甘いだけではありません!
This love isn't just sweet!
明日が今日より輝いて
May tomorrow shine brighter than today
幸せになれますように
and make me happy!
ちょっとくらい つよがりなところも許してください
Please forgive my somewhat stubborn sides.
逃げちゃダメ 避けてちゃダメ
Don't run away, don't avoid it,
後悔なんてしたくない
I don't want any regrets!
レッツゴー ハッピー らしく進もう
Let's go, happy, let's move forward as we are!
なんで!? ついてなくて
Why!? You're not keeping up,
(へこんじゃう レインデイ)
(A disappointing rainy day)
お気に入りの靴
My favorite shoes...
(水たまり ガッカリ)
(Gotten wet in a puddle, what a bummer)
なのに突然 君が突然 振り返った
And yet suddenly, you suddenly turned back
その笑顔で あつくなっていく頬に
with that smile on my cheeks growing hot,
気づかないでね
Please don't notice it!
君の手と手が触れ合って
Hand in hand, our hands touching,
伝わってるよ もう My Sweet!
It's being conveyed, already my sweet!
溢れ出す この愛を
I want to grow this overflowing love
甘い果実に育てたい!
into sweet fruit!
今日うまくいかなくたって
Even if today doesn't go well,
明日から変われるように
So that I can change starting tomorrow,
ちょっとだけ 弱気でも私を照らしてください
Even if I'm a little faint-hearted, please shine upon me!
涙ふいて 上を向いて
Wipe away your tears, look up,
止まってなんていられない
You can't just stop and stay like this!
レッツゴー ハッピー らしく進もう
Let's go, happy, let's move forward as we are!
昨日のまでの 自分にさよなら
Say goodbye to the self up until yesterday
明日はきっと 明日の太陽が照らすよ
Tomorrow will surely be illuminated by tomorrow's sun
君が好き！素直になって 言えたらどんなにso happy
I like you! If I could honestly say it, how so happy
溢れ出す この愛は 甘いだけではありません！
This overflowing love is not just sweet!
明日が今日より輝いて 幸せになれますように
May tomorrow shine brighter than today and bring happiness
ちょっとくらい つよがりな ところも許してください
Please forgive my slight bravado as well
逃げちゃダメ 避けてちゃダメ 後悔なんてしたくない
Don't run, don't avoid, I don't want any regrets
lets go happy らしく進もう
LET'S GO HAPPY, let's move forward as we are
はーい！ということでね、皆さん！改めてまして、にゃっはろー！
Hi there! So everyone, once again, Nya-hello!
エリート巫女アイドル、さくらみこだよ！
It's elite miko idol, Sakura Miko!
いやー、ということで！ついに迎えた誕生日！いえーい！
Yeah, so! The birthday has finally arrived! Yay!
はい、誕生日ということで皆さんこちら！どどん！ハッシュタグさくらみこ生誕祭でたくさんツイートしてね！よろしくね、少しもたくさんしてね！
Yes, for my birthday everyone, look here! Ta-da! Please tweet a lot with the hashtag Sakura Miko Birthday!
いやー、みこ誕生日だからかな。なんかステージが今までよりもパワーアップしていますよ！どどん！
Man, is it because it's Miko's birthday? The stage is even more powered up than before! Ta-da!
いやー、さくら風が帰る青空です！すごいねー。まだまだね仕掛けがありますけれども。
Man, it's a blue sky where cherry blossom winds return! Amazing.
いやー、なんか鳥もね、ドーンってなってて、なんかゲートもね、ドーンってなっております！
Man, even the torii gate went boom, and the gate went boom too!
たくさんありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
そして、見て！こちら、さくら風でね、入居してきました！こちらの、ききゅうに！みこぴーのききゅうだよ！
And look! Here, in the cherry blossom wind, it arrived! This hot air balloon! It's MikoP's hot air balloon!
いやついに、みこぴーも、ききゅうまで育ちましたか！いやすごいね！嬉しいね！
Has MikoP finally grown up to hot air balloons too! That's amazing! I'm so happy!
いやありがとうございます、たくさんね！ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much, everyone! Thank you!
ということで今回のライブはなんと、すごくたくさんゲストを呼んでおります！
So for this live, we have invited a whole bunch of guests!
そして、なんと！後半には新ショウもお披露目しちゃうので、皆さん最後まで見逃すなよ！
And what's more! In the second half, we'll also reveal a new shop, so don't miss out till the end everyone!
それでは、ゲストパートいきますか！盛り上がっていくぞー！
Well then, shall we go to the guest part? Let's get hyped up!
腐りかけた心にi need you 噂のアルカロイド
In a rotting heart, I need you, the rumored alkaloid
あだ名はネットの撒落工場 かきならせディストーション
Nickname is the net's gossip factory, strum out distortion
つけやいばのサムライが乱れ討ち 三段銃
The samurai of the burning blade runs amok, triple-shot
珍劇の歴史で踊ろうか ほら てんてこ 変てこ まいまい
Shall we dance in a bizarre history? Look, topsy-turvy, weird, dizzy
僕の心はエゴロック 斜め45度 4万ボルト
My heart is an ego rock, 45 degrees, 40,000 volts
脳内洗脳 明日にバイバイバイ
Brainwash, say bye-bye-bye to tomorrow
媚びへらうその姿は架空の空模様
The figure that flatters and fawns is an imaginary sky
しにかるなしせんの雨 今日もモラトリアムを塞ぐふり
Cynical, heartless rain, pretending to block moratorium today too
おちゃらけ頭にi need you ちまたのアルカロイド
In a playful head, I need you, the town's alkaloid
あの子もはやのインスタントショー 巻き散らせディスコード
That child is already an instant show, scatter discord
怒頭があがるぬサムライが未来断つ 相討ち歌
The samurai who can't get ahead cuts off the future, mutual destruction song
珍妙な歴史で歌おうか ほら ちゃんちゃら なんちゃら まいまい
Shall we sing in a ridiculous history? Look, absurd, whatever, dizzy
ロックな心で生きようか 間違いなくホットなミュージック
Shall we live with a rock heart? Without a doubt, hot music
脳内洗脳 まるかいて 明日もハハハ
Brainwash, draw circles, tomorrow is also ha ha ha
しゃらくさ ささもくせになる はみ出しものだろ
Audacious, habits become second nature, you're an outcast, right
りりかるなしせんの雨 今日もモラトリアムを開くふり
Lyrical, heartless rain, pretending to open moratorium today too
とうめいなかんじょうはそまるだけさ だったら見てみぬふりするやつらを押し倒せ
Transparent emotions just get dyed, then push down those who pretend not to see
人生かけても負けそうですか 負けとりゃかんねんすんの
Even if you risk your life, are you about to lose? If you lose, give up
生きていこう、ロックな心で
Let's live with a rock-n-roll heart...
真夏並みHotなミュージック
with summer-like hot music!
明日もハハハ
Tomorrow's gonna be haha-ha!
冴えない孤独さえ寂しくなる
Even a boring outcast gets lonely,
飛び乗る視線の先、今日も両目を開くふり
reaching out to grab the shinny future!
透明な感情は燃えるだけさ
My transparent emotions are burning up,
だったら見栄張るふりするヤツらを押し出せ
laughing at anyone who tries to look away.
僕の心はエゴロック
My heart is an ego rock,
斜め45度ノンセンス
45 degrees, 40,000 volts!
脳を砕いてマンネリを
Brainwash, shatter the routine,
明日にバイバイバイ
and say goodbye to tomorrow!
あーあー、マイクおっけー！いくよー！
Mic check! Here we go!
ミニスカートで襲撃だ、(キュン)
Attack with a miniskirt, kyun!
ギャップ燃えして衝撃だ、(キュン)
Shocked by gap moe, kyun!
恋の妄想回路暴走でまてまてほら(ブーブー)
My love fantasy circuit runs wild!
だだだだ、大好きこくってちょーだいよ(ハイハイ)
I love you so much, hey!
ビバビビビバ、ビバ・ハッピー！(チュルチュチュ)
Viva, viva, happy!
ビバビバ・ハッピー！(チュルチュチュ)
イヤイヤ、争いはしない主義のノノ・ノンノン
I have a principle never to fight!
ビバビバ・ハッピー！(チュルチュチュ)
Viva, viva, happy!
切なくってもやるせなくっても (kabaddi...)
Even if you feel sad and lonely,
あの娘になんてなれないから
you can never become her.
ありのままの自分を愛せればケセラセラ
Love yourself the way you are!
今はひとりぼっちの君に歌をあげる、ハイ、どうぞ！
I dedicate this song to you, alone right now.
ビバビビビバ、ビバ・ハッピー！(チュルチュチュ)
Viva, viva, happy!
ビバビバ・ハッピー！(チュルチュチュ)
くたくた睡眠は8時間、イェイ・イェイ・イェイ
I want to sleep for 8 hours!
ビバビバ・ハッピー！(チュルチュチュ)
Viva, viva, happy!
あれこれしたいけどしたい i my me mine キリキリ舞い
I want to try everything, I my me mine!
ハッピーに舞い踊る君が好きだよ
I love you, dancing into happiness!
ちょっと純情なピュアチャンス通り抜けも劇ティック
A bit of pure luck, but drama short-circuited.
中途半端なお説教きた、そんなに世間は甘くない、だからやめて
The world isn't as easy as they say!
スルーでアバターにチェンジ
Transform into an avatar,
バーチャルヴィーナスブーストバスでボーンニャン
virtual venus boosting with the bass!
ビバ、ビビビビ、ハッピー
Viva, viva, happy!
イヤイヤ、争いはしない主義のノノ・ノンノン
No, no, I have a principle never to quarrel!
ビバビバ・ハッピー！(チュルチュチュ)
Viva, viva, happy!
ポロポロ涙して
Every night I cry,
「そんなに世間は甘くない！」
"The world isn't so easy!"
ビバビバ・ハッピー！(チュルチュチュ)
Viva, viva, happy!
ハッピーに振る舞う君が好きだよ
I want to be happy with you!
ちょっと緊張のピンポン、ちゃんとライブ聞いて？
A little nervous, are you listening?
中途半端なお説教きた、そんなに世間は甘くないだから
Half-hearted advice, but who cares?
スルーでアバターチェンジ！
Avatar change, let's go!
バーチャルヴィーナスブーストバスでボーン！
Virtual Venus boost and born!
ビバビバ・ハッピー！(チュルチュチュ)
Viva, viva, happy!
イヤイヤ、争いはしない主義のノノ・ノンノン
I have a principle never to quarrel!
ビバビバ・ハッピー！(チュルチュチュ)
Viva, viva, happy!
アア…マイクOK
Ah, ah... mic OK!
いっくよーっ!
Here we go!
ミニスカートで襲撃だ! (キュン)
Let's get overdressed with mini skirts! (Kyun)
ギャップ萌えして衝撃だ! (キュン)
Shocked by "gap moe"! (Kyun)
恋の妄想 回路暴走 デマ デマ ホラ (ブーーブー)
Love fantasies and crazy circuits, rumors and lies! (Boo boo!)
だ、だ、だ、だ、大好き
"I, i, i, i, I love you!"
告ってちょーだいよ (ハイ ハイ)
Confess to me already! (Yeah, yeah)
だっちゅーけどクールにルーズビート聞かせて
Let me hear the cool and loose beat,
バリバリチューン
a brilliant tune!
じゃじゃじゃじゃ〜ん!
"Ta-da-da-da-dam!"
切なくて やるせなくても
Even when feeling sad and down,
(カバディ カバディ... Fight!) もう!
(Kabaddi, kabaddi... Fight!) "Hey!"
あの娘になんて なれないから
You can never become her,
(カバディ カバディ... Fight!)
(Kabaddi, kabaddi... Fight!)
ありのままの自分を 愛せれば ケ・セラ・セラ
If you love yourself as you are, qué será, será.
今はひとりぼっちの 君に歌を与える
I offer this song to you who are lonely right now.
ハイ! どうぞ
"Here you go!"
ビビビビビ...
Vi-vi-vi-vi-vi...
1・2・3 落ちてゆくシャンデリア
1, 2, 3 the chandelier comes crashing down
一斉に火を灯すネオンライト
As neon lights illuminate to match the sound
4・5＆6 鳴らしクラップ スポットライト浴びて
4, 5 & 6, clap to the beat, bathing in the spotlight
さあ、ようこそテアトルへ
Take a seat, welcome to the theatre
開演さ、イッツ・ショウ・タイム
Curtain rising, it's showtime!
タ・ラ・タ 踊る ステップ 踏んで
Ta-ra-ta, I dance and take a step
誘導 視線 は 向こう の 方
Guiding your gaze to the other side
ストップ!
Stop!
急転 直下
Taking a sudden turn downwards
心臓 は ティック ＆ トック
My heart goes tick & tack
ほら キュー ＆ アクション
Come on, cue & action!
7＆8 上がっていく 9＆10 煽っていく
7 & 8 going up, 9 & 10 fanning the flame
緊張感を解き放つこの一瞬へご招待
Invited to this moment of released tension
アンプ・アップ 僕 の 感性 を
Amp up, updating my sensitivity
アンプ・アップ 更新 中
Amp up, updating now
アンプ・アップ 君 の 感性 に
Amp up, challenging your sensitivity
アンプ・アップ 挑戦 中
Amp up, challenging now
アンプ・アップ 研ぎ澄まされていく
Amp up, honing and sharpening
アンプ・アップ この 一瞬
Amp up, this very moment
アンプ・アップ 君 の 感情 の 支配者 さ
Amp up, I'm the ruler of your emotions!
ショウタイム・ルーラー (イッツ・ショウ・タイム)
Showtime Ruler (It's showtime!)
テイク・ユー・ハイアー・ハイアー (イッツ・ショウ・タイム)
Take you higher, higher (It's showtime!)
もっとクレイジー クレイジーにしちゃって
More crazy, let's get crazy!
ショウタイム・ルーラー (イッツ・ショウ・タイム)
Showtime Ruler (It's showtime!)
テイク・ユー・ハイアー・ハイアー (イッツ・ショウ・タイム)
Take you higher, higher (It's showtime!)
もっと 自由 に 夢中 に ご招待
Freely, passionately invited!
夢見たいな時間
A dream-like time
ルー・ルー・ルー・ルーラー
Ruler, ruler, ruler!
イッツ・ショー・タイム・ハイアー・ハイアー・ハイアー
It's showtime, higher, higher, higher!
一歩一歩近づいて、一緒にしちゃって
Step by step closer, let's do it together!
ショウタイム・ルーラー
Showtime Ruler!
イッツ・ショー・タイム・ハイアー・ハイアー・ハイアー
It's showtime, higher, higher, higher!
一歩一歩夢中に、夢中に、ショウタイム
Step by step, passionately, showtime!
夢みたいな時間
A dream-like time!
さあもっと声を聞かせて頂戴よ
Now let me hear your voices even more!
湧き上がる感情の狂乱を
The frenzy of welling emotions!
君は呑み込んでさ ボクは飲み込んでさ
You swallow it up, I swallow it up
背中もひざも冷や汗も 呼吸の通りに
Back, knees, cold sweat, just like breathing
二度と孤独になんてなれないよ
You'll never be lonely again!
ボクの合図で
On my signal,
キミは合図オンステージ
You give the signal on stage!
ショウタイム・ルーラー (ルー・ルー・ルー・ルーラー)
Showtime Ruler (Ruler, ruler, ruler!)
イッツ・ショー・タイム・ハイアー・ハイアー・ハイアー
It's showtime, higher, higher, higher!
男女から覗く感性 泣きそうなほどに重なって
Sensitivities peeking from men and women overlap almost to tears
きっと快楽・暗闇・アンダーコントロール
Surely pleasure, darkness, under control
今僕らの想いは連動 キミのこと独り占めさショウタイム
Now our feelings are linked, monopolizing you, showtime!
ショウタイム・ルーラー (ルー・ルー・ルー・ルーラー)
Showtime Ruler (Ruler, ruler, ruler!)
イッツ・ショー・タイム・ハイアー・ハイアー・ハイアー
It's showtime, higher, higher, higher!
一歩一歩近づいて、一緒にしちゃって
Step by step closer, let's do it together!
ショウタイム・ルーラー (ルー・ルー・ルー・ルーラー)
Showtime Ruler (Ruler, ruler, ruler!)
イッツ・ショー・タイム・ハイアー・ハイアー・ハイアー
It's showtime, higher, higher, higher!
一歩一歩夢中に、夢中に、ショウタイム
Step by step, passionately, showtime!
可愛くてごめん
So sorry for being so cute!
私が私の事を愛して 何が悪いの?
I love myself, what's wrong with that?
嫉妬でしょうか 痛いだとか変わってるとか
Is it jealousy? Calling me cringe or weird?
届きませんね そのリプライ
I won't listen to those replies.
大好きなお洋服 大好きなお化粧で
With my favorite clothes and favorite makeup on,
お決まりのハーフツイン巻いて お出かけしよう
With my iconic half-twintails, let's go out!
日傘持って ぼっちだって
Holding a parasol, even if I'm alone,
幸せだもん
I'm happy!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute,
生まれきてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born into this world!
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cunningly cute!
かわいくてごめん
Sorry for being so cute
生まれできちゃってごめん
Sorry that I was born
あざとくてごめん
Sorry for being calculatingly cute
気になっちゃうよね？ごめん
Sorry that you can't ignore me
かわいくてごめん
Sorry for being so cute
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for working hard on myself
尊くてごめん
Sorry for being precious
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for being a girly girl
ムカつしちゃうよね？ざまぁｗ
It annoys you, right? You deserve it!
あなたはあなたのことだけどどうぞ私に干渉しないでください
That's your business, so please don't interfere with mine.
類は友を呼ぶと言うけど…届きませんね。その陰口
They say birds of a feather flock together... but I can't hear those rumors.
重い厚底ブーツ お気に入りのリュックで
With my heavy platform shoes and favorite backpack,
崩せない前髪 くしでといて お出かけしよう
My fringe won't budge, brushed and ready to go out!
軽い女？ふざけんな 重すぎっつーの！
An easy girl? Are you kidding? I'm way too heavy!
Chu！ 可愛くてごめん
Smooch! Sorry for being so cute
この時代生きててごめん
Sorry for living in this era
目立っててごめん 意識しちゃうよね？ごめん
Sorry for standing out, sorry that you notice me.
Chu！ 可愛くてごめん
Smooch! Sorry for being so cute
この時代生きててごめん
Sorry for living in this era
目立っててごめん 意識しちゃうよね？ごめん
Sorry for standing out, sorry that you notice me.
可愛くてごめん 命磨きしてごめん
Sorry for being so cute, sorry for polishing my life.
ブリットでごめん こいびとにしちゃってごめん
Sorry for being bratty, sorry for making you my lover.
ムカつしちゃうでしょざまぁｗ
It annoys you, right? You deserve it!
趣味の違い 変われ者とバカにされても 曲げたくない
Even if they mock my different tastes and call me a freak, I won't bend.
怖くもない あんたらごとき
I'm not scared of you people.
自分の見方は自分でありたい 一番大切にしてあげたい それが私
I want to be my own ally, I want to cherish myself most—that's me!
Chu！ 可愛くてごめん 生まれできちゃってごめん
Smooch! Sorry for being so cute, sorry that I was born.
Chu！ あざとくてごめん 人生楽しんでごめん
Smooch! Sorry for being calculatingly cute, sorry for enjoying my life.
Chu！ 可愛くてごめん 生まれできちゃってごめん
Smooch! Sorry for being so cute, sorry that I was born.
Chu！ あざとくてごめん 女子力高くてごめん
Smooch! Sorry for being calculatingly cute, sorry for having high girl power.
ムカつしちゃうよね？ざまぁｗ
It annoys you, right? You deserve it!
わたしの一番かわいいところ
My number one cutest place
あれ気付いちゃいましたか？
Did you notice that?
生まれて30秒で最初聞いた言葉は
30 seconds after birth, the first words I heard
当たり前にして覚えてないけど嬉しかったはず
I naturally don't remember, but I'm sure I was happy.
今でもだいたいの中身は変わってないって言うかそりゃ
Even now my core hasn't changed, well actually
中身は変わってますのでその辺でも評価！（おねがい！）
My core has changed so evaluate me there too! (Please!)
携帯のアンテナを光らせてそれが超キュートなあの頃だって知ってた
Making my phone antenna glow, knowing how super cute it was back then
って言うかアンテナって何って言ってるような私に付き合ってくれるの好き
Well, I love how you put up with someone asking "what's an antenna?"
逆にでも私のどこが好き？ねぇねぇねぇ
Conversely though, what do you like about me? Hey, hey, hey!
私の一番、かわいいところに気付いてる
You notice my number one cutest place,
そんな君が一番すごいすごいよすごすぎる！
And you are the absolute most amazing, amazing, too amazing!
そして君が知ってる私が一番かわいいの私もそれに気付いた
And the me you know is the cutest, I realized that too!
だからそれかわいい、あれかわいいなんて誰かわいい、それかわいいなんて言わないで
So don't say "she's cute" or "that's cute" or "who's cute"
私以外なんてやだなんてありえない？
Saying anyone other than me is no good, impossible!
だからそれかわいい、あれかわいいなんて誰かわいい、それかわいいなんて
So don't say "she's cute" or "that's cute" or "who's cute"
言わないで私以外なんてやだなんて言えない！
Don't say "anyone other than me", I hate it when you say that!
わたし気づいちゃいました
I've just realized something.
毎日何秒褒められなくったってあたしは
Even if I'm not praised for seconds every day,
おかえりちょっとお待ちしてるとって前に言っていたような
like you said before, 'welcome back' gets a bit sweeter,
そんなにそれ長く変じゃないけど私は言われたいタイプでした
not that it's that long or weird, but I'm the type who wants to be told that.
もっとわかりやすくていいんだよお待ちしてます
It's fine if it's easier to understand, I'm waiting for it.
なにしててもどんな顔見せてても
No matter what I'm doing or what face I'm showing,
いつもちゃんキュートだって確信してるのは
the reason I'm always certain I'm super cute
なんかこそ知らなかった退屈の運命を
is the destiny of boredom I never knew before.
人の出逢いは無理ごめん
Meeting people? No way, sorry.
逆にでもそれより楽しいよ ねえねえねえ
Instead, it's even more fun than that, hey, hey, hey!
私の一番かわいいところをよく見てる
You're looking closely at my cutest part.
そんな君が本当に超ラッキーな人すぎる
You are truly a super lucky person for that.
そして君がだんだん経ってもそう思えるように私はそれに気づいた
And so that you'll feel that way even as time passes, I realized it.
あなたもきっと私に夢中でしょ
You must be obsessed with me too,
どこか気持ちはロングレンジ想像しちゃうかな
Somewhere, you're probably imagining a long-range feeling.
それかわいい あれかわいいよって
'That's cute, that's cute too,' you say,
本当にかわいいって言って
Tell me I'm really cute!
私の一番かわいいところに気づいてる
You've noticed my cutest part.
そんな君が一番すごいすごいよ凄すぎる
You're the most amazing, amazing, way too amazing for that.
そして君が知ってる私が一番かわいいの
And the me you know is the cutest.
私もそれに気づいた
I realized that too.
私の一番かわいいところをよく見てる
You're looking closely at my cutest part.
そんな君が本当に超ラッキーな人すぎる
You are truly a super lucky person for that.
そして君がだんだん経ってもそう思えるように私はそれに気づいた
And so that you'll feel that way even as time passes, I realized it.
私の一番かわいいところに気づいてる
You've noticed my cutest part.
そんな君が一番すごいすごいよ凄すぎる
You're the most amazing, amazing, way too amazing for that.
そして君が知ってる私が一番かわいいの
And the me you know is the cutest.
私もそれに気づいた
I realized that too.
だから それかわいい あれかわいいなんて
So don't say things like 'that's cute, that's cute too'
あれかわいい それかわいいなんて言わないで
or 'that's cute, this is cute'.
私以外なんてやだ なんてありえない
I hate the thought of anyone other than me, it's impossible!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
モノクロだらけの明日なんて
A tomorrow full of monochrome,
空白だらけの世界なんて
a world full of blank spaces,
笑顔さえも枯れちゃいそうだってなんて絶対大嫌い！
I absolutely hate the thought of even smiles withering away!
虹色だらけの地図を描こう キラキラだらけに塗りつぶそう
Let's draw a map full of rainbow colors, let's paint it over with sparkles!
夢の魔法使い目指して今日も修行中！
Aiming to be a dream magician, I'm training today too!
魔法の呪文を唱えまshow
Let's chant the magic spell, show!
カラフル・マジックをご覧あれ
Behold the colorful magic!
マジカ・ポッポ・ペルカ 見て見てみんな it's ショータイム！
Magica, poppo, pelka! Look, look everyone, it's showtime!
ワン、ツー、スリーで染め上げて ビビット・カラフル・カルテット
Dye it in one, two, three, vivid, colorful quartet!
だから マジカ・ポッポ・ペルカ 夢色 世界に ご招待！
So, magica, poppo, pelka, you're invited to a dream-colored world!
笑顔 咲かせる ような 君 だけ の 魔法 を かけよう ねぇ一緒だよ ちゅっ
Let's cast a magic just for you that makes smiles bloom, hey, we're together, chu!
時には遅めのステップで
Sometimes with a slower step,
優しいメロディに揺られ
swayed by a gentle melody,
輝く音色を奏でるのも
playing a brilliant tone
なんてたって大好き！
is something I love so much!
やっぱり早めで遅れないで ワワクドキ鼓動は待ってくれない
Still, be quick and don't be late, the exciting heartbeat won't wait for you.
夢の魔法使い目指して今日も修行中！
Aiming to be a dream magician, I'm training today too!
魔法のリズムを奏でまshow
Let's play the rhythm of magic, show!
もうひとつマジックをご覧あれ
Behold yet another magic!
いっくぞー！
Let's go!
マジカル☆ポパペルカ
Magical Popaperuka
ほらほらみんな it's ショータイム！
Hey everyone, it's show time!
1・2・3で塗りまくれ
Paint it all over with 1, 2, 3
ビビットカラフル
Vivid and colorful
ゲットだからマジカル☆ポパペルカ
Got it, so it's Magical Popaperuka
夢色世界に ご招待！
You're invited to a dream-colored world!
涙 吹き飛ぶよな
Like tears blowing away,
弾けるスマホと 魔法を唱えよう
With a bursting smartphone, let's chant magic
さあ、始めようよ
Now, let's begin
あれあれ まだ私の 魅力が伝わってない？
My-my, hasn't my charm gotten across yet?
これだけじゃ終われない！
We can't end with just this!
最後にトびきりにショータイム
Finally, a sensational show time
まだ信じてない人は お気をつけください
Those who still don't believe, please beware
超最強の禁断呪文(ハイパービッグバン・ポパペルカ)
The ultimate forbidden spell: Hyper Big Bang Popaperuka
てってれー！リニューアルだぜ！
Ta-da! It's a renewal!
マジカル☆ポパペルカ
Magical Popaperuka
見て見てみんな it's ショータイム！
Look, look everyone, it's show time!
1・2・3で染め上げろ
Dye it all with 1, 2, 3
ビビットカラフル
Vivid and colorful
ゲットだからマジカル☆ポパペルカ
Got it, so it's Magical Popaperuka
夢色世界に ご招待！
You're invited to a dream-colored world!
笑顔 咲かせるような
Like making smiles bloom,
君だけの魔法を 掛けようよ
Let's cast a magic spell just for you
内緒なんだよ
It's a secret
本能が狂い始める
Instincts start to go crazy,
追い詰められたハツカネズミ
like a cornered mouse.
今、絶望の淵に立って
Now, standing in an abyss of despair,
踏切へと飛び出した
I jumped into the railway crossing.
そう 君は友達
Yes, you're my friend,
僕の手を掴めよ
so take my hand.
そう 君は独り
Yes, you're alone,
居場所なんてないんだろ
you've got nowhere to go, do you?
二人きりの狭間
In the narrow gap between just us two,
愛し合えるさ――。
we can love each other...
繰り返す フラッシュバック・蝉の声
It repeats: a flashback, buzzing cicadas...
二度とは帰らぬ君
and you, who will never come back.
永遠に千切れてく お揃いのキーホルダー
Our matching keychains torn apart for all eternity.
夏が消し去った 白い肌の少女に
The girl with pale skin that summer erased,
哀しい程取り憑かれて仕舞いたい
I want to be possessed by her so much it brings me to tears.
本能が暴れ始める
True nature begins to run wild,
九月のスタート告げるチャイム
the start of September, announcing the chime.
次の標的に置かれた花瓶
The vase placed at the next target—
仕掛けたのは僕だった
the one who set it up was me.
そう 君が悪いうんだよ
Yes, it's your fault,
僕だけを見ててよ
look only at me.
そう 君の苦しみに 助けが欲しいだろ
Your suffering, you want help, don't you?
溺れてくその人に そっとキスをした――。
Upon those drowning hands, I gently placed a kiss...
うす笑いのけものたち その心晴れるまで
The smiling beasts, until their hearts clear up,
爪を突き立てている 不揃いのスカート
sharpen their claws, the mismatched skirts.
夏の静寂を切り裂くような悲鳴が こだまする教室の窓には青空
A scream cutting through the summer silence echoes across the classroom window.
そう 君は友達
Yes, you're my friend,
僕の手を掴めよ
so take my hand.
そう 君は友達 僕の手を掴めよ
So, you are my friend. Grab my hand.
そう 君がいなけりゃ 居場所なんてないんだよ
So, if you weren't here, I'd have no place to belong.
透き通った世界で
In this translucent world,
愛し合えたな
we were able to love each other.
繰り返す フラッシュバック・蝉の声・
Repeating flashbacks, the voice of cicadas,
二度とは帰らぬ君 永遠に千切れてく
you who will never return, tearing apart forever,
お揃いのキーホルダー
our matching keychains.
夏が消し去った 白い肌の少女に悲しい程取り憑かれてしまいたい
I want to be possessed so sadly by the pale-skinned girl whom summer erased.
透明な君は僕を指差してた
The transparent you was pointing at me.
はーい、というわけで ここまでライブやってきましたが、みんな見て! じゃじゃーん!
Hi there! So, we've done this much of the live, everyone look! Ta-da!
新衣装をお披露目しましたー! かわいいでしょ?
I unveiled my new outfit! Isn't it cute?
いやあ、あ、こちらね ピンクのセーラー服となっております!
Man, oh, this here is a pink sailor uniform!
ミコの一番のお気に入りはね、このベレー帽! かわいいでしょ?
Miko's number one favorite thing is this beret! Isn't it cute?
かわいいでしょ? えへへへ、えへっ
Cute, right? Hehehe, hehe.
はーい、ということでなんと、実はまだお披露目があるんですよ!
Alright, so surprisingly, actually there's still another unveiling!
え、気になる? え、それが、こちら!
Eh, you curious? Eh, that is, right here!
はーい! というわけで、ミコの新しいオリジナルソングが出ます! この曲はね、ミの大好きな『さえないヒロインの育てかた』のオープニングなどを手掛けている、沢井美空さんに作っていただきました! ありがとうございます! やったー、とってもうれしい!
Hi! So, Miko's new original song is coming out! This song was made for me by Miku Sawai, who handled the openings and such for Miko's favorite 'Saekano: How to Raise a Boring Girlfriend'! Thank you very much! Yay, I'm so happy!
もう本当に大好きなのり、本当に、本当にいい曲なので、ぜひ聴いてください!
I truly love it so much, it's a really, really great song, so please be sure to listen to it!
本日の3月5日の24時から、え、楽曲配信されるので、みんなチェックしてねー!
Starting at 24:00 today, March 5th, um, the song will be distributed, so everyone check it out!
とゆーことで、このあと、なんと、その曲は歌っちゃいます! それでは、みなさん、聴いてください、『ハートオンライン』!
And with that, after this, amazingly, I'm going to sing that song! Well then everyone, please listen, 'Heart Online'!
言いかけた言葉を飲み込んで
Swallowing the words I started to say,
あれっ不具合(バグ)かな ストップしちゃって
huh, is this a bug? It just stopped,
何も言わなくたってキミは
even without saying anything, you
なんでもわかってくれるけど
understand everything, but
カッコつけてもつかなくて
even when I try to look cool, it doesn't work out,
失敗ばかりでごめんね
I'm sorry for always messing up,
だけど言いたいことがあるよ
yet there's something I want to say.
もうちょっと あとちょっと 強くなりたいな
Just a little more, a little more, I want to become stronger.
キミのためならね
For your sake, you see.
ハートオンライン 気持ちまるごと
Heart Online, with all my feelings,
乗せる電波 伝わるかな?
will these radio waves carrying them reach you?
大好きだって 大切だって
That I love you, that you're precious to me,
ホントはいつも言いたいのに
even though I always want to truly say it.
きっと ねぇ きっと 会えなくても
Surely, hey, surely even if we can't meet,
キミとだから 繋がれるよ
because it's with you, we can stay connected.
ひらひらと舞う キミがくれた
Fluttering and dancing, the heart you gave me
ハートが集まって さくらになる
gathers together and becomes cherry blossoms.
分岐ルートで戸惑うたび
Whenever I'm lost at a branching route,
正解なんてわかんないけど
not knowing what the right answer is,
一緒に探し当てた今日に
on this day we searched and found together,
いつも胸がいっぱいになるの
my heart always feels so full.
ひとりだけ立ち止まってる
Standing still all by myself,
そんな気がしてた夜にも
even on nights when I felt that way,
キミが見せてくれた景色に
in the scenery you showed me,
もう一歩 あと一歩 踏み出してみたいな
I want to take just one more step forward,
そう思えたんだ
that's what I was able to think.
ぜんぶオンライン ダメなところも
Even online, even with my flaws,
キミなら笑ってくれるよね?
you'll smile for me, won't you?
着飾るよりもありのままで
Rather than dressing up, just as I am,
そんな勇気をくれたから
because you gave me that courage,
きっと ねえ きっと 負けそうでも
I'm sure, hey, I'm sure, even if I might lose,
何度だって花開くよ
flowers will bloom no matter how many times.
ひらひらと舞う キミがくれた
Fluttering and dancing, the heart you gave me
ハートが集まって さくらになる
gathers together and becomes cherry blossoms.
舞い落ちて 雨に流れる
Falling fluttering down, washed away by the rain,
そんな一瞬のユメでも
even in such a fleeting dream,
睫毛の先 ふわり触れて
brushing softly against the tips of my eyelashes,
煌めいた キミがいた
there was you, shining brightly.
さくら色のいまが 宝物だから
Because this cherry-blossom-colored present is my treasure,
ハートオンライン 気持ちまるごと
Heart online, carrying my feelings all together,
乗せる電波 伝わるかな?
I wonder if these radio waves will reach you?
大好きだって 大切だって
\"I love you,\" \"You're precious to me,\"
ホントの気持ち伝えるよ
I'll convey my true feelings.
きっと ねえ きっと 会えなくても
I'm sure, hey, I'm sure, even if we can't meet,
キミとだから繋がれるよ
I can connect with you because it's you.
ひらひらと舞う キミがくれた
Fluttering and dancing, the heart you gave me
ハートが集まって さくらになる
gathers together and becomes cherry blossoms.
私のこと知ってますか?
Do you know about me?
可愛く見えてますか?
Do I look cute to you?
私の歌どうだろうな
I wonder how my singing is;
うまく歌えてますか?
am I singing well?
衣装だとかメイクだとか
Clothes, makeup, and such—
可愛く見えてますか?
do I look cute?
振付とかファンサとかも
Choreography and fanservice too—
喜んでもらえますか?
are you happy with them?
手は冷たくなって 足は震える
My hands grow cold, my legs tremble,
それでも戦いたい アイドルだから
but still I want to fight, because I'm an idol.
バカにする奴は嫌いだ 見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate people who mock me, I hate being looked down on.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を 見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't casually say things like \"just an idol\" without even looking.
頑張りを当然と言うな イメージとか強制するな
Don't call working hard a given, don't force images on me.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
I hate the phrase \"just an idol\" more than anything in this world.
プライベート見えないから 分からないと思います
Since you can't see my private life, I suppose you don't know,
性格とか悪い方です 騙しちゃっていますか?
my personality is pretty bad—have I been deceiving you?
でも本気です本気なんです ありのままの私を
But I'm serious, I really am. Accept me just as I am,
好きになって推してください それってワガママですか?
love me and support me. Is that too selfish of me?
きっと可愛くない全部分かってる
I know I'm definitely not cute, I know all of that,
それでも好かれたい アイドルだから
but still I want to be liked, because I'm an idol.
皮肉言う奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make cynical remarks.
言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
I hate endless excuses.
“こんなものか”という言葉は
Words like "Is that all it is?"
軽々しく口にするな
shouldn't be said so casually.
勝手に限界決めるな
Don't arbitrarily decide my limits.
笑い者になんてするな
Don't make a laughingstock out of me.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
The phrase "just an idol"
この世で一番大嫌いだ
is what I hate most in this world!
向い風を切り裂け
Slice through the headwind,
誇り高きアイドル
a proud idol!
応援がなければ活動できない
I can't be active without your support.
好きなことばかりじゃ生きてはいけない
I can't just live doing only what I love.
元気あげるはずがもらってばかりだし
I'm supposed to give you energy, but I always end up receiving it.
恩返しできる日まで待っててね
Please wait until the day I can repay you.
歓声が減っても 飽きられちゃっても
Even if the cheers fade, even if people get tired of me,
それでも笑っていたい
I still want to keep smiling.
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol.
熱いファンの愛があって
With the passionate love of my fans,
スタッフさんの愛があって
with the love of the staff,
いつも家族の愛があって
with the constant love of my family,
生きてる“アイドル”
I'm living as an "idol"!
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who mock me,
見下されるのも嫌いだ
and I hate being looked down upon.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を
The phrase "just an idol"
見てもいないくせに言うな
shouldn't be said by those who don't even watch.
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't call my hard work something to be expected.
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force your image upon me.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
The phrase "just an idol"
この世で一番大嫌いだ
is what I hate most in this world!
みんな いつもありがとう！
Everyone, thank you as always!
これからも頑張るから応援よろしくね！
I'll keep doing my best, so please keep supporting me!
大好きだよ！
I love you all!
はーい、ということでみなさん！ライブ楽しんでもらえましたかー？
Alright, so everyone! Did you enjoy the live?
たくさんお祝いしてくれて本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for celebrating with me!
えー、先ほど披露した「酔うたい焼き」は、このあと24時から配信開始なのでぜひダウンロードしてね！
The song "You Taiyaki" I just performed will be available at midnight tonight, so please download it!
そして最後にドロドロっと告知でーす！
And finally, here comes a rush of announcements!
この度なんと、さくらみこ×明利酒類さんとのコラボが決定しましたー！
Sakura Miko's collaboration with Meiri Shurui has been decided!
その名も、「酔うたい焼き さくらみこすぺしゃる」！
Appropriately named, "You Taiyaki Sakura Miko Special"!
明利酒類さんで発売の「たい焼きに合う 酔うたい焼き」をみこイメージでさくら風味にしていただいた限定商品です！
It's a limited product by Meiri Shurui tailored to Miko with cherry blossom flavor!
わあ、ありがとうございます！え、ラベルのイラストはさとうぽてさんに描き下ろしていただきました！
Wow, thank you! The label illustration was freshly drawn by Satou Pote!
お値段、税込みなんと3,500円！3日後の3月8日水曜日17時から明利酒類さんのオンラインショップにて発売予定なのでお楽しみに！
The price is 3,500 yen including tax! It goes on sale March 8th at 5 PM on Meiri Shurui's online shop!
さらにさらに、こちら！ドーン！
And even more—this! Tada!
みこの誕生日記念グッズが出まーす！わあ！早速詳細を見ていくぞ！
Miko's birthday commemorative merch is out! Wow! Let's check the details right away!
はい、ということでこちら！2層アクリルパネル！え、新春のみこを描いてもらいました！おるだん先生いつもありがとうございます！
Here it is! A 2-layer acrylic panel featuring my New Year outfit! Orudan-sensei, thank you as always!
そして、みことおそろいリュックサック！あの新春のね、みこのリュックの、命がけです！まあね、ここにね、みこぴーのぬいぐるみをもふーんと入れてもよし！
And the matching Miko backpack! That New Year Miko backpack—it's life or death! You can stuff a Mikopii plush right inside!
そして、35P着ぐるみマスコットキーホルダー！みこがみこぴーの着ぐるみをつけています！かわいい！
Next, the 35P Kigurumi Mascot Keychain! Miko is wearing a Mikopii kigurumi! So cute!
そして、こちらタンブラー！これはね、普段使いしてもらいたいなと思っております！もうずっと作りたかった！イェイ、使ってね！
And this tumbler! I wanted you to use this everyday! I've wanted to make one for so long! Yay, please use it!
そして、フルセット！フルセット購入特典はなんと、数量限定で直筆サイン入り！がんばって書くぞー！たくさん！たくさん！
And the full set! The full set bonus includes a limited handwritten signature! I'll do my best to sign them all!
ということで、こちらおるだん先生描き下ろしイラストのポストカードがついてきまーす！
And a postcard featuring newly drawn illustrations by Orudan-sensei is included!
あっ、通常限定間に合わなくても、
Ah, even if you don't make it in time for the regular limited version,
抱き枕サインとかメッセージがね、あの、用意してありますので。
we've prepared things like hug pillow autographs and messages.
ぜひ、あの、安心してね。
So please, rest assured about that.
でもすぐに買ってね！
But buy it right away!
間に合うようにね、頑張ってね。はい！
Do your best to be in time, okay? Yes!
そして皆さん、どどーんと告知、
And everyone, how was the big reveal
いかがでしたでしょうか！いやあ、
and announcement? Man,
いやあ、でも、緊張したね！ねえ？
man, that was so nerve-wracking, right?
いやでもね、このあとはなんと、
But you know, after this, what's more,
まだまだあります！全身で、なんと、
there's still more! In full 3D, what's more,
ガチ恋キッ！ガチ恋ディスタンス！シチュエーションの
a Gachikoi Kiss! Gachikoi Distance! situation
配信をするのでやってはみますけどね、
stream is coming up, so I'll try doing it,
需要あるのかって感じですけどね！
though I wonder if anyone actually wants to see that!
ぜひみんな見に来てね！
Everyone, please come watch!
それでは！みんな誕生日お祝いしてくれて、ありがとう！
And with that! Everyone, thank you so much for celebrating my birthday!
大好きだよ！
I love you all!
ま、い、まーい！
B-Bye-bye!
桜風に揺るる空
A sky swaying in the cherry blossom breeze,
君と出合ったこの場所で
in this place where I met you.
どんなときも側にいて
Stay by my side no matter what,
笑顔咲かせてね
and let your smile bloom.
足並み揃えて
Walking in step together,
君の手と手が触れ合って
our hands touch and intertwine,
伝わってるよ
and it reaches my heart.
僕の心はエゴロック 斜め45度
My heart is Ego Rock at a 45-degree angle,
マンネリをウハウ砕いて 明日にバババババ
crushing the monotony and heading into tomorrow with a bang!
ハートを重ねて
Overlapping our hearts,
次へ進もうよ
let's move forward to the next step.
きみに届け
Reaching out to you,
スペシャルな笑顔を
giving you a special smile!